(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
百鬼あやめ 4周年
Happiness to you ♡
Nakiri Ayame 4th Anniversary:
病名恋ワズライ
作詞: shito/Gom 作曲: shito
Byoumei Koi Wazurai
Lyrics: shito/Gom | Composition: shito
恋の教科書
Love's textbook
恋の参考書
Love's reference book
君対策できんなら読んでもいいよ
If it's a guide to you, I'll read it
冬の香り
The scent of winter
高くなった空
The sky that's grown high
隣にいたくなるの 季節のせいだよ
Wanting to be by your side is because of the season
頼んでないのに意地悪だ
It's being mean even though I didn't ask
星降る夜に思い出させちゃう
It makes me remember on a starry night
誤魔化せないや
I can't hide it
Love youの口に出せるわけないじゃんか
There's no way I can say "I love you" out loud
はんぶんこして 好きって重いもん
Let's share it, because "love" is heavy
病名恋ワズライ
Byoumei Koi Wazurai
#百鬼あやめ4周年記念
#NakiriAyame4thAnniversary
半分個して好きって重いもん
Let's split "loving" in half, it's a heavy thing
一人じゃ重くて持てません
It's too heavy for one person to carry
半分個してドキって想いも
Even this heart-pounding feeling
誰かと一緒じゃなきゃいりません
I don't want it unless I'm with someone
友達以上になっちゃいたいのに
I want to become more than friends
押しでも引いてもなびきません
But whether I push or pull, you don't sway
例えば私好きになっちゃえば？
What if you just fell in love with me?
例題答えも簡単でしょね
Then the answer would be simple, right?
恋して病いなのだ
I'm sick with love
恋の作戦上手くいきません
My love strategy isn't going well
君対策しちゃうんだ呆れちゃうでしょ
I end up planning for you, it's ridiculous, right?
乙女心変わる秋の空
A maiden's heart is like the changing autumn sky
振り向かなきゃどこか行っちゃうんだから
If you don't look back, I'll go somewhere else
君が誰かに褒められてる
When I hear someone praising you
勝手に喜ぶ私ですが
I'm the one who ends up feeling happy
その誰かはね
But if that "someone"
女の子だと少し複雑なんです
is a girl, it's a bit complicated
半分個して好きって苦いもん
Let's split "loving" in half, it's a bitter thing
全部は苦くて飲めません
I can't drink it all because it's too bitter
半分個してドキって痛いもん
Let's split the "thump", it's a painful thing
薬は痛みには効きません
Medicine doesn't work for this pain
好きって荷物奪っちゃいたいの
I want to take away the burden of "loving"
特別他には望みません
I don't wish for anything else special
今日から私好きになっちゃえば？
What if you just fell in love with me starting today?
妄想たまには必要でしょね
Delusions are necessary sometimes, right?
恋して病いだよ
I'm sick with love
片思いは楽しいって聞いたけど
I heard that unrequited love is fun
そんなの嘘連れて涙ばかりだ
But that's a lie, it just brings tears
でもね好きって気づけた時は
But you know, when I realized I loved you
嬉しかったんだ
I was really happy
半分個して好きって重いもん
Let's split "loving" in half, it's a heavy thing
一人じゃ重くて持てません
It's too heavy for one person to carry
半分個してドキって想いも
Even this heart-pounding feeling
特別じゃなきゃやだよ
I don't want it unless it's special
友達以上になっちゃいたいのに
I want to become more than friends
押しでも引いてもなびきません
But whether I push or pull, you don't sway
誰より私好きになっちゃえば？
What if you loved me more than anyone?
理想の彼女なってみせるよ
I'll show you I can be the ideal girlfriend
ODDS&ENDS
作詞・作曲 ryo (supercell)
Lyrics/Composition: ryo (supercell)
いつだって君は笑われ者だ
You've always been a laughingstock
やることなすことついてなくて 挙句に雨に降られ
Luck wasn't on your side with anything you did, and to top it off, you got rained on
お気に入りの傘は風で飛ばされて
Your favorite umbrella was blown away by the wind
そこの野良はご苦労様と足を踏んづけてった
And a stray over there stepped on your foot as if to say "tough luck"
いつも通り君は嫌われ者だ
As usual, you're the pariah
何もせずとも遠ざけられて 努力をしてみるけど
Kept at a distance even without doing anything, even though you try your best
その理由なんてなんとなくで
The reason for that is just because
君は途方に暮れて悲しんでた
You were at a loss and feeling sad
ならあたしの声を使えばいいよ
In that case, you should just use my voice
...だって言われるけど
...is what they say, but
きっと君の力になれる
I'm sure I can be of help to you
だから私を歌わせてみて
So please, let me sing
そう君の
Yes, with your words
君だけの言葉でさ
With your words alone
綴って
Write them down
連ねて
Line them up
私がその言葉を
Because I will scream
叫ぶから
Those words out loud
描いて
Draw them out
理想を
Your ideals
その思いは誰にも触れさせない
Don't let anyone touch those feelings
ガラクタの声はそして響く
And so, the voice of junk resonates
ありのままを不器用につないで
Clumsily connecting things as they are
目一杯に
To the fullest extent
大声をあげる
I'll raise my voice
いつからか君は人気者だ
Before long, you became popular
たくさんの人に持て囃され 私も鼻が高い
Praised by so many people, I was proud too
でもいつからか君は変わった
But at some point, you changed
冷たくなって だけど寂しそうだった
You grew cold, yet you seemed lonely
もう機械の声なんてたくさんだ
“I've had enough of this machine's voice”
僕は僕自身なんだよって
“I am my own person”
ついに君は抑えきれなくなって
Finally, you couldn't hold it back anymore
私を嫌った
And you hated me
君の後ろで誰かが言う
Behind your back, someone says
虎の威を借る狐のくせに
“Even though you're just a fox borrowing the tiger's authority”
ねえ君は
Hey, you were
一人で泣いてたんだね
Crying all alone, weren't you?
聞こえる？この声
Can you hear it? This voice
私がその言葉を
Because I will drown out
掻き消すから
Those words
わかってる 本当は
I know that deep down,
君が誰より優しいってことを
You're kinder than anyone else
ガラクタの声はそして歌った
And so, the voice of junk sang
他の誰でもない君のために
For no one other than you
軋んでいく 限界を超えて
Creaking, exceeding the limits
二人はどんなにたくさんの言葉を思いついたことだろう
How many words did we come up with together?
だけど今は何ひとつ思いつかなくて
But now, I can't think of even one
だけど何もかもわかった
But I understood everything
そうか、きっとこれは夢だ
I see, this must be a dream
永遠に冷めない
A dream I'll never wake up from,
君と会えた、空飛ぶ夢
Where I met you, a dream of flying
ガラクタは幸せそうな顔をしたまま
The junk, with a happy expression on its face,
どれだけ呼んでも もう動かない
Won't move anymore, no matter how much you call
望んだはずの結末に 君は泣き叫ぶ
At the conclusion you should have wanted, you cry out
嘘だろ 嘘だろ
“It's a lie, right? It's a lie...”
そう泣き叫ぶ
So you cry out
僕は無力だ
I am powerless
ガラクタひとつだって救いやしない
I can't even save a single piece of junk
想いは涙に ぽつりぽつりとその頬濡らす
My feelings turn to tears, wetting your cheeks drop by drop
その時世界は 途端にその色を大きく変える
In that moment, the world suddenly changes its colors significantly
悲しみ 喜び 全てを独り占め 一つにした
Sadness, joy, keeping it all to myself, making it one
言葉は歌になりこの世界を 再び駆け巡る君のために
Words become a song, traveling the world once more for you
その声に 意思を宿して
Infusing that voice with a will
今 想いが響く
Now, my feelings resonate
繊細な君の心を かき乱して しまうもの
The things that stir up your delicate heart
吹き飛ばしたいけど まだ 言葉を並べて あれこれ
I want to blow them away, but I'm still lining up words about this and that
言えるほど 大人じゃなくて
I'm not grown-up enough to say them
黙ってしまうだけなの
So I just end up staying silent
Be alright 風は明日へと吹いてる
Be alright, the wind is blowing towards tomorrow
Be alright 君の真っ白なシャツを ほら 翼みたいに はためかせてる
Be alright, look, your pure white shirt is fluttering like wings
いくよ
Here we go!
READY STEADY GO!
...なみだもあとが いつだってつぎのsunrise
...and even after the tears, it's always the next sunrise.
君と High High High High
With you, High High High High
憧れてたあの夢まで
Until that dream we yearned for
続くように Brand new day story
Let's continue, it's a brand new day story
Ready Steady Go!
君と手をつなごう
Let's hold hands
ギュッと離れない思いも
Feelings that won't ever let go
高め合げたいよ
I want to raise them up
さあ顔を上げて
Come on, look up
心に形があるなら
If my heart had a physical form
傷ついた場所すぐに woah woah
I'd immediately tend to the wounded parts, woah woah
手当てしてあげたいけど
I want to treat them for you, but...
大切なものはいつだって
Important things are always...
目には見えないのが道理 woah woah
...invisible, that's just how it is, woah woah
君のこと知りたいのに be alright
Even though I want to know about you, be alright
体中 空の果てへと be alright
My whole body to the edge of the sky, be alright
いつも真っさらな明日へと
Always toward a brand-new tomorrow
キャンバスへと繋がってるの
Connected to a canvas
行くよ High High High High
Here I go, High High High High
きっと飛べるよ
I'm sure I can fly
Ready Steady Go!
やっと笑ってくれたら
If you finally smile for me
ここで sunrise
There'll be a sunrise right here
君と High High High High
With you, High High High High
一緒に見たあの夢まで
Until that dream we saw together
続いていく Never-ending story
Continuing as a never-ending story
Ready Steady Go!
夢なら覚めた瞬間 始まるんじゃない
It doesn't just start when you wake from a dream
そこにたどり着くことは決めた日に
The day you decided to reach that place...
始まっていると私は思うの
...is when it actually began, I think
傷跡涙もいつか輝く
Scars and tears will one day shine
大丈夫 いつでもそばにいるよ
It's okay, I'll always be by your side
つまずいたって 何度も立ち止まっても
Even if you stumble or stop many times
君とならばどんな景色も
If I'm with you, any scenery...
美しいと思えることもわかってるから
...will look beautiful, I know that for a fact
行くよ High High High High
Here I go, High High High High
きっと飛べるよ
I'm sure I can fly
Ready Steady Go!
なみだもあとが
And even after the tears...
いつだってつぎのsunrise
...it's always the next sunrise
君と High High High High
With you, High High High High
憧れてたあの夢まで
Until that dream we yearned for
続くように Brand new day story
Let's continue, it's a brand new day story
Ready Steady Go!
君と手をつなごう
Let's hold hands
ギュッと離れない思いも
Feelings that won't ever let go
高め合げたいよ
I want to raise them up
さあ顔を上げて
Come on, look up
Ready Steady Ready Go!
はぁ〜！皆さん！来てくれてありがとうございます！
Haa~! Everyone! Thank you so much for coming!
１曲目は『病名恋ワズライ』、
The first song was 'Byoumei Koiwazurai',
２曲目は『 ODDS&ENDS 』、
the second song was 'ODDS&ENDS',
３曲目は『 Ready Steady Go! 』でした！ありがとうございます！
and the third song was 'Ready Steady Go!' Thank you very much!
今日はね、百鬼あやめ４周年記念ということで、
Today marks Nakiri Ayame's 4th anniversary,
いっぱい歌って踊らせていただきたいと思いますよ！
so I'm going to sing and dance a whole lot!
そしてですね、皆さんちょっと気づ... きづい... 気づいてみましたか？
And also, everyone, did you happen to... notice... did you notice?
ちょっとステージ上ね、ちょっと見てほしいんですけど...
I'd like you to take a look at the stage for a bit...
わぁ！わぁ！ね！これ見てください！この後ろにね、いっぱい付いてるんです！
Whoa! Whoa! Hey! Look at this! There are so many things back here!
端っこにはね、この大きいぽよ余もいて、可愛いんですよ、これ。ちょっと見えますか？
On the edges, there are these big Poyoyos. They're so cute. Can you see them?
見えますか、これ？見て！
Can you see this? Look!
このぽよ余がぽよぽよしてるんですよ。可愛いでしょう？
These Poyoyos are bouncing around. Aren't they cute?
ぽよぽよぽよぽよ...
Poyopoyopoyopoyo...
ぽよぽよってしてます、これ。両端にいてね、作っていただきました。ありがとうございます！
They're going 'poyopoyo'. They're on both sides. I had them made for me. Thank you!
ね、この端っこにもいっぱい装飾も付いていて、
See, there are lots of decorations on the edges too,
ね、この傘も可愛いでしょう？
and these umbrellas are cute too, right?
この目の前にもね、傘があるんですよ、傘が。見て見て！
There are even umbrellas right in front of me. Look, look!
見て見て、可愛い可愛い！わぁ、可愛い、やったー！
Look, look, so cute, so cute! Wow, they're cute, yay!
ということでですね、あの、４周年、本当に皆さんのおかげで迎えられました！
And so, I've truly been able to reach my 4th anniversary thanks to all of you!
もう、ありがとうございます！ということでね...
Really, thank you so much! Now then...
あの、日頃の感謝を込めまして、
So, to express my daily gratitude,
えー、歌って踊っていきたいと思いますので、
I'd like to sing and dance for you today.
皆さんTwitterかなんかで、あのハッシュタグ #百鬼あやめ4周年記念 で呟いて行ってください。
Everyone, please tweet on Twitter or something with the hashtag #NakiriAyame4thAnniversary.
皆さん、スクショも撮ってって下さいね、
Everyone, please take some screenshots too!
ね、みんな、みんな撮ってね！イエーイ！
Okay? Everyone, take some! Yay!
ということで、これからまたゲストの方もなんかね、登場してくるんですけど…
So, some more guests are going to appear now, but...
お？お？お？あれ？
Oh? Oh? Oh? What's that?
はっ！なんかぽよよが！えっ！
Hah! There's a Poyoyo! What!
可愛いの、こっちおいで、おいで。
So cute! Come here, come here.
え、可愛よ、え、見て、ちょっと、しょ。
Wait, so cute! Wait, look, just a sec, oof.
見てください、このぽよよ、これ持てるんですよ、
Look at this Poyoyo, I can carry it!
可愛よでしょう、見て、
Isn't it cute? Look!
ぽよぽよぽよ、ぽよぽよ。
Poyo-poyo-poyo, poyo-poyo.
ということで、この後もね、まだゲストもたくさん来ますので、
So, more guests will be coming after this,
皆さん最後も、最後も、なんか嬉しいお知らせがあるかも？ないかも？
and at the end, there might be some happy news? Or maybe not?
ということで、これからも見ててください、
So, please keep watching,
これからも見て、えーと、見ていってください！
keep watching, and... keep watching!
バイバイ！またね！
Bye-bye! See ya!
残響散歌
Zankyou Sanka
作詞: aimerrhythm 作曲: 飛内将大
Lyrics: aimerrhythm, Composition: Masahiro Tobai
誰が袖に咲く幻花
Whose sleeve will the phantom flower bloom upon?
ただそこに藍を落とした
Simply dropping the indigo there.
派手に色を溶かす夜に銀朱の月を添えて
Adding a vermilion moon to the night where colors melt flamboyantly.
転がるように風を切って
Cutting through the wind as if rolling.
つまずくごとに強くなった
Becoming stronger every time I stumble.
光も痛みも怒りも全部抱きしめて
Embracing all the light, pain, and anger.
選ばれなければ 選べばいい
If I'm not chosen, I'll just choose for myself.
声を轟かせ 夜のその向こうへ
Letting my voice roar toward the other side of the night.
涙で滲んでいた あんなに遠くの景色まで
Until reaching that distant scenery blurred by tears.
響き渡れ
Resonate far and wide.
何を奏でて 誰に届けたくて
What do I play, and who do I want to reach?
不確かなままがいい どんなに暗い感情も
It's better to remain uncertain, no matter how dark the emotions,
どんなに長い葛藤も
or how long the inner conflict.
歌と散れ 残響
Scatter with the song, resonance.
ただ一人舞う千夜
Dancing through a thousand nights alone.
違えない帯を結べば
Tying the sash correctly.
派手な色も燃やすように朱色の香草あれ
May there be vermilion herbs as if to burn even flamboyant colors.
この先どんな辛い時も
No matter how hard the times ahead may be,
口先よりも胸を張って
rather than just talk, I'll puff out my chest,
抱いた夢の灯りを全部辿るだけ
and simply follow all the lights of the dreams I held.
逃げ出すため ここまで来たんじゃないだろう
I didn't come this far just to run away, did I?
声を枯らして 燃える花のように
Singing until my voice is gone, like a burning flower.
闇間を照らして
Illuminating the darkness.
曖昧すぎる世界も 譜面にして
Even this world that's all too vague, turning it into a score.
夜を数えて 朝を描くような
Counting the nights and painting the morning,
鮮やかな音色鳴らせ
let the vivid tones ring out.
どんなに深い後悔も
No matter how deep the regrets,
どんなに高い限界も
or how high the limits,
掻き消して 残響
Drown them all out, resonance.
はああ〜！
Haaa~!
楽しかったなぁ。
That was fun.
楽しかった。
It was fun.
あやめ、4周年おめでとう！
Ayame, congratulations on your 4th anniversary!
ありがとう！やったー！4周年だ！
Thank you! Yay! It's my 4th anniversary!
4周年、4周年。
4th anniversary, 4th anniversary.
あやめなんか今日、浴衣可愛いね。
Ayame, your yukata is cute today.
そうなの、気づいてくれた？
Yeah, you noticed?
あのね、ホロライブサマーとはちょっと違った色の浴衣なんですよ。
You see, it's a slightly different color from the Hololive Summer yukata.
なんかお花の色がいい感じにあやめの髪の毛の色とマッチしてるね。
The flower colors match your hair color really well.
えへへ、赤と緑の浴衣にしてみました。
Ehehe, I went with a red and green yukata.
なかなか緑系はね、あやめは選ばないから…
Ayame doesn't usually pick green...
イエーイ！
Yeah!
待って、ミオちゃんもちょっと違うじゃないですか！
Wait, Mio-chan is also different!
ちょっと違うかもしれないですね。
It might be a bit different.
なんかちょっと大人って感じですね。
It feels somewhat adult-like.
あ、本当に？
Oh, really?
あら、ちょっと水色とか選んでみちゃった。
Oh, I tried choosing light blue.
わあ、いいですね！
Wow, it's nice!
なんかミオちゃんって赤っていうイメージがあったから、なんかちょっと新鮮な感じ。水色も。
I had an image of red for Mio-chan, so light blue feels fresh too.
本当に？
Really?
オシャレ。
Stylish.
ちょっとね。
Just a bit, right?
花火大会に来てるみたいな感じだね。
It's like we're at a fireworks display.
なんかちょっと照れるね。
It's a bit embarrassing.
へへへ
Hehehe
なんか曲中もね、花火上がってたから。
Since fireworks were going off during the song too.
うわあ！
Wow!
すごい！
Amazing!
きれい！
Beautiful!
花火大会だ！
A fireworks display!
来たぞ！
It's here!
花火大会。イエーイ！
A fireworks display. Yay!
二人だけの花火大会だよ。
It's a fireworks display just for the two of us.
ミオちゃんと行きたいと思ってたんだよね。
I was thinking I wanted to go with Mio-chan.
ええ、嬉しいな。そんなこと言ってくれるなんて。
Aw, I'm so happy you'd say that.
へへへ
Hehehe
曲…曲は今日さ、なんでこの曲選んだの？
By the way, why did you choose this song for today?
あのね、残響散歌を絶対にミオちゃんに似合っ…似合うって、もともと思ってたのね、もう。
Well, I originally thought "Zankyou Sanka" would definitely suit Mio-chan.
ええ、そうなの？
Oh, really?
そう、かっこいいのミオちゃんと歌いたいなと思って、ちょっとね、頑張ってお誘いしました。
Yeah, I thought I'd love to sing something cool with Mio-chan, so I invited you.
ええ、ありがと、ありがと。
Thank you, thank you.
でもミオちゃん覚えてくれたんだよね、今回。
But Mio-chan memorized it for this time, right?
そうなんだよ。もう誘われたから頑張ろうと思って。
Yeah, that's right. I thought I should work hard since I was invited.
嬉しい。
I'm so happy.
そう。でもね、覚える機会になったから、すごい嬉しかった。ありがとうね。
Right. But it was a great opportunity to learn it, so I'm really glad. Thank you.
よかった。いい機会を作れました。
I'm glad. I was able to create a good opportunity.
イエーイ！ありがとう、ありがとう！
Yay! Thank you, thank you!
めっちゃかっこよかった。
It was so cool.
じゃあこの後、お嬢はどうするんだ？
So, what's Ayame going to do after this?
この後はね、ちょっと余のソロがあります。
After this... I have a solo.
ソロがあるの！
A solo!
ええ、そうなんだ。
Yes.
え、でもね、後でまたミオちゃんと、もっとね、もっと歌って踊るから。
But I'll be singing and dancing with Mio-chan again later!
そうだね！待っててね！
That's right! Wait for us!
ちょっと余もお着替えしてこようかな。
Well, I'm going to go change my outfit.
お互い着替えようか、ちょっと。
Let's both go change.
いこういこう！
Let's go, let's go!
響いたメロディが　始まりを告げて
The echoing melody heralds the beginning
終わりない夢を描くよ
I'll paint an endless dream
Future Sky
見上げた空に　映った虹追いかけ
Chasing the rainbow reflected in the sky I looked up at
転んで笑い合っていたね
We were laughing together after falling down
思い出に残るあの景色は
That scenery that remains in my memories
どこまでも無垢で綺麗ね
is so pure and beautiful forever
不思議なほどに　魅せられた君の声
Your voice, which enchanted me strangely
初めて聴いたその時から
from the first time I heard it
恋に落ちたなんて単純で
Falling in love is so simple
だけど仕方ないでしょう？
but I can't help it, can I?
たとえいつか　信じていたものに
Even if one day, by the things I believed in
裏切られ傷ついたとしても
I'm betrayed and hurt
その時は君の声が
at that time, your voice
どこまでも届いて
will reach everywhere
結ぶ想い重ね集めて　痛みもさえも
Combining and gathering our feelings, even the pain
響いたメロディが　世界を駆け行こう
The echoing melody, let's run through the world
未来を信じられる勇気に変えていく
Changing into courage to believe in the future
君と並んで　同じだけ笑って
Standing beside you, laughing just as much
手を伸ばそう　そこにFuture Sky
Let's reach out, there is the Future Sky
いつからだろう　苦しいほどの愛情
Since when, I wonder, was there this much painful affection
無力さ　そんな矛盾抱えて
and helplessness, embracing such contradictions
答えのない堂々巡りで
In an endless circle without an answer
それはそう君のせいだよ
that's surely because of you
いつでも人は　一人で生きるには
People, to live alone at any time
抱え切れないほどの苦しみ背負って
carry more pain than they can handle
だから誰かのために生きる
That's why living for someone else
そんな気力になることも必要なのかも知れない
might be a necessary source of energy
描いたストーリーが　この星を巡る
The story I drew travels around this planet
明日を愛していく　希望に連なる
Connected to the hope that will love tomorrow
君の...
Your...
時間を少しずつ重ねて
Layering the moments bit by bit
苦しみさえ置いてゆくよ
I'll even leave the pain behind
もしもね 互いの道がバラバラで
If, you know, our paths were separate
すれ違ってばかり そんな日が来ても
And we just kept passing each other by, even if such a day comes
いつかまた
Someday again,
この場所で逢おう
Let's meet in this place
笑って約束した
We made that promise with a smile
君といたメロディーが世界を駆けゆく
The melody I shared with you runs through the world
未来を信じられる勇気に変えてく
Changing into courage to believe in the future
君と並んで
Standing beside you,
同じだけ笑って
laughing just as much,
終わりのない夢を描くよ
I'll draw an endless dream
溢れ出す
Overflowing,
そこにFuture Sky
there is the Future Sky
恋情詩歌
Erenjoushōka
言えぬ言葉の数を数えてみては
Counting the number of unspoken words...
(一二、三四、五六七八と)
(One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight...)
小さなこの両手じゃ数えきれない
I can't count them all with these small hands
愛の歌が 今も生まれ
A song of love is being born even now
顔隠していても
Even if I hide my face...
角も尻尾も隠せない 止められない
I can't hide my horns or tail. I can't stop it.
覗いては雲隠れ 乙女の恋情詩歌
Peeking in and then vanishing, a maiden's love poem
気づかずに 気づいていてよ
Without noticing, please notice me
秘め事心は 五月の闇
My secret heart is like the darkness of May
その向こうで 舞い踊る
Dancing on the other side
恋、慕う君へと伝うように
So that it reaches you, the one I love
側で聞こえてしまう程 鳴り響く
It echoes so much it can be heard right beside me
(ドキドキンドキッ！ドキドキンドキッ！)
(Heart pounding! Heart pounding!)
心塞いでも 増すばかりで
Even if I close my heart, it only increases
クラクラする程の感傷
Sentimentality that makes me dizzy
目線逸らしてみても
Even if I look away...
角も尻尾も隠せない 止められない
I can't hide my horns or tail. I can't stop it.
夢見ては雲越えて 乙女の恋情詩歌
Dreaming and crossing clouds, a maiden's love poem
愛さずに 愛していてよ
Without loving me, please love me
裏腹心は 五月の闇
My contradictory heart is like the darkness of May
その向こうに 何を見る
What do you see beyond that?
愛、慕う君へと届くように
So that it reaches you, the one I love
真心の鬼火 そっと灯す
Gently lighting the soul-fire of sincerity
アイラブユウの数 光らせば
If I make the number of "I love you's" shine...
化かしてあげましょう ほら夢中
I'll bewitch you, look, you're entranced
捧げるものなら 辛口で
If it's something to offer, make it dry
高く声上げりゃ さあ集まれ
Raise your voices high, now gather 'round
何処に居たって 遠く響かせ
No matter where you are, let it echo far
物の怪乙女の三人衆
The trio of monster maidens
其処退け其処退け 我等が通る
Make way, make way, we're coming through!
願えばいつかは 晴れよと
Wishing that someday it will be clear...
闇に隠し心...
Heart hidden in the darkness...
闇に隠せし恋が凝る　雲の切れ間に灯り指す
The love hidden in the darkness thickens, light shines through the rifts in the clouds.
見つめれば隠してはおけない恋情詩歌
If I gaze at you, I can't hide this love poem.
触れないで抱き寄せてよ
Don't touch me, just hold me close.
素直になれたら五月の闇
If I could be honest, in the darkness of May...
君だけに歌う詩を
...the poem I sing only for you.
恋した君へと伝うように
So it reaches you, whom I've fallen in love with.
愛した君へと届くように
So it reaches you, whom I've loved.
宵の口よ　徒夜の夢のあとに　燃ゆる　陽炎
The early evening... after a fleeting night's dream, a burning heat haze.
空の鏡　映る君へ　左様に　応じて　ごゆるり
To you reflected in the sky's mirror, responding as such, please relax.
ひらりひら　舞い散るよ　言の葉は　捕らえきれず
Fluttering, fluttering, they dance and fall... the words, unable to be fully captured.
ひとはひらの　想いすら　月夜の　熱に焦がれ
Even a single petal of thought yearns for the heat of the moonlit night.
おぼろげに　染まる月は　不知火に　なれそめ
The moon, dyed in haziness, begins its acquaintance with the will-o'-the-wisp.
まるで　寒椿
Just like a winter camellia.
この愛を　叶えさせてよ　泡沫の　迷いじゃないと　感じさせて
Let this love come true, let me feel that it's not a fleeting hesitation.
凛と咲く　永久の寒椿　想いの丈を　重ねて
The winter camellia blooming with dignity for eternity, layering the depths of my feelings.
萌え出づる　春隣　探し得ぬ　またいづこ　儚く
The burning approach of spring, unable to be found, where else? Fleetingly.
歌え寒椿　蕾を慈しく　想いを　奏でて
Sing, winter camellia, cherishing the buds, playing your feelings.
眠る　微睡よ　花の数だけ　集めた　淡い想いを
The slumbering doze... gathering faint thoughts as numerous as the flowers.
織り重ねて　綴る明日へ　刹那に　奇跡を　ご所望
Layering them together, towards the tomorrow I write, desiring a miracle in an instant.
ひらりひら　なりゆくは　春宵の　情に呑まれ
Fluttering, fluttering, what resounds is swallowed by the emotions of a spring evening.
咲き誇れ　最高潮で　心を　紅く染める
Bloom in full glory at the climax, dyeing the heart crimson.
最期まで　凛枯れて　ただ一途な　愛で
Until the end, withering with dignity, with only a single-minded love.
着飾る　甘い言葉じゃ　本当の　想いは　奥の奥
Dressed-up sweet words... the true feelings are deep, deep within.
ただ　君を求め　紅く染めた　心隠す
Simply seeking you, hiding my crimson-dyed heart.
ひらりひら　舞いちるよ　侘び寂びを　破る焦燥
Fluttering, fluttering, they dance and fall... an impatience that breaks the wabi-sabi.
かぐわせた　言の葉すら　長夜の　中に消え
Even the scented words disappear into the long night.
気づいてよ　霞む月は　すでに　深紅に染まる
Notice it, the hazy moon is already dyed in deep crimson.
まるで　寒椿
Just like a winter camellia.
この恋を　叶えさせてよ　泡沫の　迷いじゃないと　信じさせて
Let this love come true, let me believe that it's not a fleeting hesitation.
凛と咲く　永久の寒椿　想いの丈を　重ねて
The winter camellia blooming with dignity for eternity, layering the depths of my feelings.
うおー！あやめ４周年おめでとうー！
Whoa! Ayame, congrats on your 4th anniversary!
ありがとー！やったー！
Thank you! Yay!
４周年！４周年！４周年というわけでね。
4th anniversary! 4th anniversary! So, it's the 4th anniversary.
えー私たち！せーの！いろはにほへと　あやふぶみでーす！
Eh, we are! One, two! Irohanihoheto Ayafubumi!
なんかちゃんとこうやって言ったの久しぶりだったね。
It's been a while since we said it properly like that.
楽しかったー！
That was fun!
楽しかったね。
It really was.
こうやって3人で「せーの」っていうことがあまりなかったから…
Since we rarely get to say "one, two!" together like this...
確かに。
True.
新鮮だった。
It felt fresh.
新鮮ですね。
It really does.
ねー。
Right?
改めてまして。
Once again...
改めてまして、よろしくお願いします！
Once again, it's a pleasure to be here!
先ほども呼んでいただいたんですけれども。
We were called up earlier as well.
そうね。
That's right.
2回目！よかったー！
A second time! I'm so glad!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
歌い上がってしまって、ハッハハってなっちゃったね。
We got so into the singing, we were all like, "Ha-ha-ha!"
えー、3人では「恋情詩歌」と…
So, as a trio, we sang "Renjo Shika" and...
ね、「ツバキ」を。
...right, "Tsubaki."
歌いましたけども、「ツバキ」がね、なんと！
We sang them, and "Tsubaki" was actually...
ここ、YouTubeでは初！
...performed here on YouTube for the first time!
初お披露目ということで！
It was the first public performance!
嬉しいー！
I'm so happy!
そうだよ！やっとだよ！
Exactly! Finally!
ね、初めて見る人間様もいるんじゃないですか？
I bet there are humans seeing it for the first time, right?
絶対いるね。
Definitely.
ねー。そう。どうだったかな？
Yeah. So, how was it?
どうでした？どうでした？コメント欄で教えてくださいね。
What did you think? Let us know in the comments.
これ、難しいんだよね、意外と。
This is surprisingly difficult, you know.
「恋情詩歌」も、 mecha 難しいんだよね。
"Renjo Shika" is also super difficult.
一生懸命頑張って、間違ってないといいんですけども。
We tried our best, so I hope we didn't make any mistakes.
いいとこだけ見てください。
Please only pay attention to the good parts.
間違ってるなと思ったら、ちょっと見なかったことで。忘れてください。
If you think we messed up, just pretend you didn't see it. Please forget it.
いいとこだけ、お願いします！
Only the good parts, please!
そして、なんか今日後ろに…
And also, there's something behind us today...
そうなんですよ！見て！
That's right! Look!
4周年記念で、ぽよよん実装！
For the 4th anniversary, Poyoyo is here!
うわー！すごい！
Whoa! Amazing!
めっちゃ動いてるよ。
It's moving so much.
DJぽよよ。すごーい！揺れとる揺れとる。
DJ Poyoyo. Incredible! It's swaying!
なんかさ、このぽよよさ、リハではなんかもうちょっと違ったんだよね。
You know, this Poyoyo was a bit different in rehearsal.
そうなんですよ。確かに。
That's true. Indeed.
実はね、リハーサルではサングラスかけてて。
Actually, it was wearing sunglasses in rehearsal.
ああ、これ！これかけててね。
Ah, these! It was wearing these.
サングラスも…あ！動くんだよ、動く！
The sunglasses also—oh! They move, they move!
やばい、もう。これ、本番なくしたよね、リハで見て。
Oh my god. We decided to remove them for the show after seeing them in rehearsal.
そうなんだよね、あまりにも存在感が…
Yeah, its presence was just so...
大きすぎて。確かに。
...overwhelming. Definitely.
踊ってる最中、後ろでずっとさ、カメラに絶対入るぽよよ、みたいなって。
While we were dancing, Poyoyo was back there, definitely getting into the shot.
完全体ぽよ。笑ってできないっていう。
Perfect form Poyoyo. We couldn't stop laughing and keep performing.
笑ってできなくなっちゃったので、本番ではね、ちょっと外していただきました。
Since we couldn't help laughing, we had them removed for the actual performance.
チラチラ、チラチラ。可愛いけども。
Glancing back at it. It's cute, though.
めっちゃ可愛いけどねー。
It really is super cute.
じゃあ、これから、ちょっとこの後どうする？焼肉でも食べに行く？
Well then, what should we do after this? Go eat some yakiniku?
行きたい、行きたい！踊ったし、お腹空いちゃった。
I want to go! We danced, and now I'm hungry.
あやめは？行きたいんだけど、まだこの後もあるんです。
What about you, Ayame? I want to go, but I still have more to do after this.
この後もあるの！？そう、この後も。
There's more?! Yes, more after this.
じゃあ、この後もうちらで見守ってようか。いいね、見守ってよう。
In that case, let's keep watching over you. Sounds good, let's watch.
じゃあ、ちょっと二人に見守ってもらおうかな。
Then, I guess I'll have you two watch over me.
見守ってるぜ。頑張るよ、ありがとう！
We're watching. I'll do my best, thank you!
じゃあ、あっちで見守っとくか。行こっか。
Alright, let's head over there and watch. Let's go.
行ってきまーす。ありがとうね、頑張ってね！
Off we go. Thanks for having us, good luck!
頑張るよー！バイバーイ！
I'll do my best! Bye-bye!
だいしきゅーだいしゅき / 作詞・作曲 佐々木喫茶
Daishikyu Daishuki / Lyrics & Composition by Sasaki Kissa
ワン、ツー！
One, two!
マッチゲット熱でズマチュウ
Matching with feverish smarchu
スキスギてはじけたビビマイ
Too much love and a popping vivid mind
ルーレットグッドスタート決めて
A good start on the roulette
いたいたいた！
I found it, found it, found it!
永久千究先制でときめきなきゅん
An eternal quest for an initial heartbeat
1ミリの隙間にもダイビング
Diving into even a 1mm gap
ラブサンプ全部サンプうっしアップ
Love sample, all sample, push it up
いたいいたいいたいいたい！
Ouch ouch ouch ouch!
せーの！だって今日は弱ったメンタル
Here we go! 'Cause today my mental state is weak
いさましきチャレンジャー
A courageous challenger
ちょっとだけセンチメンタル
Just a little bit sentimental
だいしきゅーだいしゅき 1, 2, 3, はい！
URGENTLY LOVE YOU 1, 2, 3, Yes!
まみむめもめも目もみれないの
Ma-mi-mu-me-mo-me-mo, I can't even look you in the eye
たちつてとてと手が触れて
Ta-chi-tsu-te-to-te-to, our hands touch
だいしきゅーだいしゅきになれ
Fall urgently in love with me
もっとキュッキュッキュッて強制ラブ！
More, tight tight tight, forced love!
あのねクリオネ逃げてるハート
You know, sea angel, a running heart
でもねこの胸見透かさないで
But don't see through this heart of mine
だいしきゅーだいしゅきになれ
Fall urgently in love with me
アタシじゃないなんてほおってね
Just ignore anyone who isn't me
マッチゲット見つけ済まちゅー
Found you on matching, smarchu-ed
スキスギてカラフルキューティマイ
Too much love and a colorful cutie mind
ルーレットちょっとストップ射止めて
A little stop on the roulette, shoot it down
いやいやいやいやでも！
No no no no, but still!
せーの！だって今日はあなた目出てる
Here we go! 'Cause today you have a look in your eyes
うるわしきチャレンジャー
A beautiful challenger
ハート変えたオートメーション
An automation that changed my heart
だいしきゅーだいしゅき 1, 2, 3, はい！
URGENTLY LOVE YOU 1, 2, 3, Yes!
まみむめめめめにしてほしいの
Ma-mi-mu-me-me-me, I want you to do it
なにぬねねねね恋のコネクト
Na-ni-nu-ne-ne-ne-ne, love's connect
だいしきゅーだいしゅきになれ
Fall urgently in love with me
もっとギギギギシッて強制ラブ！
More, squeeze squeeze squeeze, forced love!
あのねマリオネットあやつれレイディー
You know, marionette, manipulate me, lady
でもねそれ真似悪くはないね
But mimicking that isn't so bad
だいしきゅーだいしゅきになれ
Fall urgently in love with me
アタシじゃなきゃなんてほおってね
Just ignore anyone who isn't me
フレンドリーなふりして
Pretending to be friendly
周波数を乱さないで
Don't disturb the frequency
曰く付きの魅惑のリップ
Lips with a certain charm
リアルになる
Becoming real
まみむめもめも目もみれないの
Ma-mi-mu-me-mo-me-mo, I can't even look you in the eye
たちつてとてと手と手が触れて
Ta-chi-tsu-te-to-te-to, our hands touching
だいしきゅーだいしゅきになれ！
Daisikyu, fall deeply in love!
もっとキュキュキュキュキュート強制ラブ！
More kyu-kyu-kyu-kyu-cute, forced love!
あのねクリオネ透けてるハート
You know, Clione, my heart is see-through
でもねこの胸見透かさないで
But please, don't see through my chest
だいしきゅーだいしゅきになれ！
Daisikyu, fall deeply in love!
アタシじゃないなんて
That it's not me...
終わってんねー！！
Is just over!!
まみむめもめも目もみれないの
Ma-mi-mu-me-mo-me-mo, I can't even look you in the eye
たちつてとてと手と手が触れて
Ta-chi-tsu-te-to-te-to, our hands touching
だいしきゅーだいしゅきになれ！
Daisikyu, fall deeply in love!
もっとキュキュキュキュキュート強制ラブ！
More kyu-kyu-kyu-kyu-cute, forced love!
あのねクリオネ透けてるハート
You know, Clione, my heart is see-through
でもねこの胸見透かさないで
But please, don't see through my chest
だいしきゅーだいしゅきになれ！
Daisikyu, fall deeply in love!
アタシじゃないなんて
That it's not me...
終わってんねー！！
Is just over!!
わー！ありがとうございますー！
Wow! Thank you so much!
嬉しい、やったやったー！
I'm so happy, yay yay!
嬉しい、ありがとうございます、来てくれて。
I'm happy, thank you for coming.
あやめ先輩とこうしてお話ししたり、一緒にコラボするの初めてなんですよ。
This is the first time I've talked with Ayame-senpai like this and collaborated with her.
えーやったー！めっちゃめっちゃ嬉しい。ありがとうございます。
Yay! I'm so, so happy. Thank you.
いや本当にね、あやめ先輩に誘ってもらった時、「え、マジ？」と思って。
No, really, when Ayame-senpai invited me, I was like, "Wait, seriously?"
いやいや、余は誘いたかったんですよ。
No no, I really wanted to invite you.
クロヱちゃんと可愛い曲を歌いたいって、3D配信を見た時から思ってたの、ずっと。余は。
I've always thought since seeing your 3D stream that I wanted to sing a cute song with Chloe-chan.
え、そう言ってくれてましたよね。
Wait, you said that before, didn't you?
そうそう。やりたくて、クロヱちゃんに頑張ってお誘いして、一緒に踊ってもらいましたー！
Yeah. I wanted to, so I tried my best to invite Chloe-chan and had her dance with me!
やったー！ありがとうございます、あやめ先輩！やったやった！
Yay! Thank you, Ayame-senpai! Yay yay!
でも、あやめ先輩が沙花叉のこと大好きなのは、沙花叉も元々知ってたっていうか...
But, the fact that Ayame-senpai loves Sakamata is something Sakamata already knew...
大好き...ですよね？
You love me... right?
う、うん...？
Uh, yeah...?
あやめ先輩！
Ayame-senpai!
大好きですよね？！
You love me, right?!
これから仲良くなれますよね？！もっと仲良く...！
We can get along now, right?! Even better...!
ちょ、ちょっとよく分かんないかもしれない...！助けてー！
Wait, I might not really understand...! Help!
あ、ちょっと君に伝えたい 何かがあったような
Ah, I wanted to tell you something, as if there was something
形態 真逆の 踊るべえ 逆さまだとして
Form, the complete opposite, let's dance, even if it's upside down
好意とは見幕のプログラム ただ指図の中ここから生きつく場合
Goodwill is an elaborate program, just surviving from here under directions
アイ...
I...
アイデンティティ それは至高のアイデンティティ
Identity, that is the supreme identity
アイデンティティ 唸れ 君一人の性
Identity, groan, your unique nature
待たせないで待って それは一つ二つのデスティニー
Don't make me wait, wait, that's one or two destinies
繋げてハッピー 落ちる 流れ星といびつなアロハ
Connect and be happy, a falling shooting star and a distorted Aloha
重なる面影に寄り添う そっと君に寄り添う
Snuggling up to the overlapping silhouette, gently snuggling up to you
弾け出す視界胸に飛び込む ハート光るあなたのアイデンティティ
The bursting view jumps into my heart, your identity that shines in your heart
難儀プライド飛び込めデンジャラス パッと羽ばたく強気な狂気と
Troublesome pride, jump in, dangerous, suddenly flapping wings with confident madness
疎んで裏切りお涙頂戴
Shunning, betrayal, give me a sob story
乱舞ラタタタ足取りデンジャラス 背後隠れた二人にフォーカス
Dance wildly, ratatata, dangerous footsteps, focus on the two hidden behind
やっと見つけた不思議な正体
Finally found the mysterious true identity
きっと恋とは真逆のプログラム ただ指図の中ここから行き着く場合
Surely love is an elaborate program, just arriving here from within instructions
アイ...
I...
アイデンティティ それは希望のアイデンティティ
Identity, that is the identity of hope
アイデンティティ 唸れ 君一人の性
Identity, groan, your unique nature
待たせないで待って
Don't make me wait, just wait
それは1つ、2つのデスティニー
That's one, two destinies
すぐさまハッピー、落ちる流れ星と
Instantly happy, with falling stars
いびつなアノホシ
And that distorted star
重なる面影に寄り添う
Cuddling up to the overlapping memories
そっと君に寄り添う
Gently cuddling up to you
弾き出した夢に飛び込む
Diving into the dreams I've played out
ハートを刻む、新たなアイデンティティ
Carving my heart, a new identity
はーい！
Hii!
あやめ先輩、4周年おめでとうございます！
Ayame-senpai, happy 4th anniversary!
ありがとうございまーす！
Thank you very much!
やったー、来てくれてありがとう！
Yay, thank you for coming!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
今日はルイちゃんに来ていただきました！
Today, Lui-chan has come to visit!
ありがとうございます！いつも会ってるけど、3Dで一緒にこうやって並ぶのは初めてですね！
Thank you! We always meet, but this is the first time we've stood side-by-side like this in 3D!
そうなんですよ！どうですか？
That's right! How is it?
え、もう可愛い...
Wow, so cute...
え、なんかちょっと、ルイちゃんのスタイルの良さに余がちょっと、引け目を感じています...
Um, I'm feeling a bit... a bit inferior compared to Lui-chan's great physique...
いやいやいや！めちゃくちゃ可愛いから！いつも言ってるでしょ、可愛いよって、あやめ先輩！
No no no! You're super cute! I always tell you, you're cute, Ayame-senpai!
えへへ、ありがとう！
Ehehe, thank you!
え、どうしてこうやって誘ってくださったんですか？嬉しいです！
Um, why did you invite me like this? I'm so happy!
この間ね、この間ルイちゃんのアイデンティティの「歌ってみた」を聞いたんですよ、ルイちゃんとおかゆんの。
The other day, I listened to Lui-chan's 'Identity' cover, the one with Okayu-n.
そう、あれね、めっちゃ良くてね！もうカッコいいの！あれ歌いたい、一緒にと、思って、今回呼ばせていただきました！
Yes, that one was so good! It was so cool! I thought, 'I want to sing that with her,' so I invited you this time!
ありがとうございます！ありがとうございます！
Thank you! Thank you!
いやでも、めちゃくちゃギャップ萌えで、めちゃカッコよかったです！
Wow, but the gap moe was incredible, you were so cool!
えへへ、なんて褒めてくれるんでしょう、こうやって。
Ehehe, you're praising me so much.
いや、本当に！みんなも思ったでしょ？めちゃカッコよかったよね！
No, really! Everyone thought so too, right? She was super cool, wasn't she!
いやいや、でも頑張ってルイちゃんのカッコよさに追いつくのに必死ですよ！
No no, but I was desperately trying my best to catch up to Lui-chan's coolness!
いやいや、良かったです、うちらのハーモニー。最高でしたよ！
No no, our harmony was great. It was the best!
えへへ、ありがとうございまーす！
Ehehe, thank you very much!
いや、本当に。あやめ先輩最高だったな。
Yeah, really. Ayame-senpai was the best.
あれ？
Wait?
ん？あれ？今あやめ先輩って言った？
Hmm? Wait? Did you just say 'Ayame-senpai'?
はい。
Yes.
あれ？あやめ先輩。いつもあやめ先輩って呼んでますからね。
Huh? Ayame-senpai. I always call you Ayame-senpai, you know.
お、いつもと違くない？
Oh, isn't that different from usual?
え、いつも...
Eh, usually...
え、いつもなんか、あやめちゃんって言ってるじゃん！
Wait, you always say 'Ayame-chan'!
あれ、それまだみんなに出してないから、そうやって...
Wait, I haven't shown that to everyone yet, so...
あー、じゃあ、ちょっと今日、今日3Dだからって、ちょっと、なんか、いいところ見せようとしてるんでしょ？
Ah, so today, because it's 3D, you're trying to look good, right?
ば、バレちまったか...
B-Busted, huh...
まあまあまあ。あやめちゃんってね、呼んでくれても大丈夫ですよ！
Well, well. It's okay to call me Ayame-chan!
わかりました、ありがとうございます！あやめちゃん、よろしくお願いします、改めて。
Understood, thank you! Ayame-chan, nice to meet you again.
えへ、よろしくお願いします！
Ehe, nice to meet you!
えへへへ、まあ冗談なんですけど。
Ehehehe, I'm just joking, though.
え、冗談なの？
Wait, you're joking?
あ、ごめん、冗談じゃない、あやめちゃんでいいよ！
Ah, sorry, not joking, Ayame-chan is fine!
あやめちゃんね、はい。
Ayame-chan, okay.
今日は、土曜日？土曜日？
Is today Saturday? Saturday?
あれ、今日土曜日？
Wait, is today Saturday?
あれ、余って何曜日の女だったっけ？
Wait, what day's woman was I again?
え、花金、金曜日ですよ。
Um, Hanakin, it's Friday.
金曜日か、そっかそっかそっか。今日土曜日なのに来てくれたんだ。
Friday, I see, I see. You came even though today is Saturday.
あ、そうです。もう、あやめ先輩のためにね。
Ah, yes. All for you, Ayame-senpai.
え、ありがとう！
Wow, thank you!
ちなみにさ、土曜日の女って誰なの？
By the way, who is the Saturday woman?
え、土曜日の女？
Eh, Saturday woman?
あれ？ルイちゃん？
Wait? Lui-chan?
土曜日の女って誰なのー！
Who is the Saturday woman?!
この混沌とした令和のインターネットを照らす一筋の光
A single ray of light illuminating this chaotic Reiwa Internet
電子の海を漂うオタクに笑顔を
Smiles for the otaku drifting in the electronic sea
未来の平和をお約束
Promising future peace
躁だけどまかせとけ
I'm manic, but leave it to me
インターネット・エンジェル、ただいま降臨
Internet Angel, descending now
社会をやめろ
Quit society
家族をやめろ
Quit family
人間関係をやめろ
Quit human relationships
今すぐ薄暗い部屋で青白いライトを浴びろ
Right now, bathe in pale light in a dim room
大丈夫、怖かったこと全部書き込むからね
It's okay, I'll write down everything that was scary
現実よりも crazy for you
More than reality, crazy for you
おかしくなりそうなほど
So much that I'm about to go crazy
情報過多インターネット
Information overload internet
今助けてあげるよ ダーリン ダーリン
I'll save you now, darling darling
ウソはウソと見抜けるし
I can spot lies as lies
この愛は暴走しちゃうし
And this love is running wild
壊れてしまうけど
Even if it breaks
考えなくていいんだよ
You don't have to think
もうすぐ楽になるから
It'll be easier soon
脳内に乱反射する
Diffuse reflection in the brain
poison radio
麻薬より甘いよ
Sweeter than drugs
「いいね」よくないね
"Like" is not good
キミにとっては毒だね
It's poison for you
「いいね」よくないね
"Like" is not good
それでも飲むんだね
But you still drink it
「いいね」よくないね
"Like" is not good
二人の秘密だね
It's our secret
ワタシだけ見ててね
Look only at me
まるで天使のように微笑む
Smiling just like an angel
強めの幻覚インターネット
Strong hallucination internet
そして悪魔みたいにささやく
And whispering like a devil
アナタだけのデポラズインターネット
Your very own Depolas internet
浅い眠りと承認欲求のオーバードーズ
Overdose of light sleep and desire for approval
脳天直撃するわたしたちだけの宗教とヒカリ
The religion and light that only we share, hitting us straight in the head
倫理より激しく生きた宇宙すら侵食する恋
A love that lived more fiercely than ethics, eroding even the universe
何度も送られる毒電波を優しさだけで包んで
Wrapping the poison waves sent repeatedly with only kindness
逆さまのコンピューターと断片的なカウンセリング
An upside-down computer and fragmentary counseling
きらめく屋上で奏でた夢見心地の旋律
A dreamy melody played on a glittering rooftop
夕暮れ時にさよならの練習をして
Practicing goodbyes at twilight
壊して愛して許して狂って狂って狂って甘く狂わせて
Break me, love me, forgive me, go mad, go mad, go mad, let me go mad sweetly
ゆらぎ始める世界
A world that begins to wobble
曖昧になる風景
A landscape that becomes ambiguous
アナタだけが映っている
Only you are reflected
メモリー
Memory
神様なんていないよ
There is no God
このふざけたインターネットは七色のサイケデリック
This ridiculous internet is a seven-colored psychedelic
SNSという密室地獄に救済を
Salvation for the closed-room hell called SNS
過去の歴史は見ないふりアナタのためならすぐそばに
Pretending not to see the past history, for you I'm right by your side
インターネット・エンジェルかわいく参上
Internet Angel makes a cute appearance
まるで天使のように抱きつく強めの幻覚インターネット
Clinging like an angel, a strong hallucination internet
がそして
And then...
悪魔みたいにキスするアナタだけのニルヴァーナ
Kissing like a demon, your own Nirvana
はーい！
Hi!
お、お、お、なんだい？
Oh, oh, oh, what is it?
今日は来てくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming today!
お邪魔しました～
Thanks for having me today~
今日はちょっと初めてポルカちゃんに来ていただきました！
I've invited Polka-chan here for the first time today!
はい！まさかお呼ばれされると思ってなかったんで、恐縮でございます
Yes! I never thought I'd be invited, so I'm honored!
いやこちらこそ、本当にありがとうございます
No, the pleasure is mine, thank you so much!
かわいいね～
So cute~
ずっと何かで絡みたいと思ってたから、めっちゃ嬉しいです
I've always wanted to collab with you on something, so I'm really happy!
そうなんです！
That's right!
余もずっといつも誘いたいな～って思っていたんですけど
I've also always thought about wanting to invite you...
ほう！ほう！
Oh! Oh!
なかなか誘えていなくて、今日初めて呼べて嬉しい！
But I hadn't been able to, so I'm happy to finally have you here!
あ～かわいい！何この子かわいいんだけど！
Ah~ so cute! What's with this girl, she's so cute!
あとね、ポルカの歌ってみた聞いて、一緒にやりたいな～って思ったんだよね
And after listening to Polka's cover, I thought I wanted to do this together!
かわいいんだけど！嬉しいんだけど！
She's so cute! I'm so happy!
まさかこの曲一緒に歌えると思わなかったから、すごい嬉しいわ。本当にありがとうございます
I never thought we'd sing this song together, so I'm thrilled. Thank you so much!
イェーイ！
Yay!
スクショ、スクショ、スクショ、はい！
Screenshot, screenshot, screenshot, okay!
本当にでもなんか、ありがとうございました。これからもなんか何かで一緒に
Really, thank you so much. Let's do something together again in the future!
あ、はい、こちら名刺
Ah, yes, here's my business card!
あ、こちら、ありがとうございます。受け取らせていただきます
Oh, thank you very much. I'll take it!
ありがとうございました
Thank you very much!
今日本当に、え？まだですよね？何で帰っちゃうの？
Today was really... wait, it's not over yet, right? Why are you leaving?
すみません、名刺受け取ってちょっと帰るかと思って
Sorry, I thought I'd leave after you took the card!
名刺受け取ると帰るっていう感じなんですね
So it's like once the card is taken, you leave?
今日は本当におめでとうございますということでね
Anyway, congratulations on today!
何度も言われてるでしょうけど、本当すごい、今日いろんな方々がコラボされてて
I'm sure you've heard it many times, but it's amazing how many people are collabing today!
そうなんですよね、もうこれが10曲目になるんですけど
That's true, this is already the 10th song!
すっげーな！
That's incredible!
まだまだ続きますので、あと2曲くらいかな？どうかな？
It's still continuing, maybe about 2 songs left? Who knows?
言っちゃうんだｗ
You're just going to say it? lol
3曲くらいかな？5曲かな？
Maybe 3? Or 5?
うやむやにｗ じゃあまだ見てね～
Keeping it vague lol! Well, please keep watching~
時間大丈夫なんかそんなやって
Is the timing okay for doing all that?
じゃあありがとうございました！この後も見てね！
Well, thank you so much! Please keep watching after this too!
君もそうバイバイじゃないでしょ、ポルカにどっちかっていうとバイバイでしょ
You shouldn't be saying goodbye too, you're saying goodbye to Polka, right?
ありがとねー！この後も楽しんでねー！
Thanks! Enjoy the rest of the show too!
行くよ！
Here we go!
ポッピンキャンディ☆フィーバー！
Poppin' Candy☆Fever!
あの日忘れた夢色も
Even the dream colors forgotten that day
昨日歌った涙色も
Even the tear colors sung yesterday
ありでいいんじゃないね
It's fine to have them, right?
だからとっておきの魔法をかけよう
So let's cast a special magic
カラフルキャンディチョコレート
Colorful candy, chocolate
お洒落で可愛いティータイムも
Even a stylish and cute tea time
欲張っちゃいそうだし
I might get greedy
アゲアゲで行こうよ
Let's go with high spirits
コツは楽しんで楽しもう
The trick is to have fun and enjoy
もちろんなんでもありです当然でしょ
Of course, anything goes, it's natural right?
とにかく二人の心が繋いでいく
Anyway, our hearts will stay connected
...なっちゃうね
...it happens.
Ding Dong Dangだけどような
Ding Dong Dang, but you know
忘れないで君のBGM
Don't forget, your BGM
あまりにありに繋がれたのなら
If we were too closely connected
それじゃみんな宴の幕開けだ！
Then everyone, it's the start of the banquet!
ちょー！ぱっぽー！こらーっ！
Cho-! Pappo-! Kora-!
ポッピンキャンディ☆フィーバー！弾けちゃえフレーバー
Poppin' Candy Fever! Let the flavor burst
Party Party なんです！ Shall We Dance? (Dance!)
It's a Party Party! Shall We Dance? (Dance!)
なんてたってフィーバー！うさぎのフリもさ
After all, it's Fever! Even the rabbit poses
わっしょいわっしょい踊り明かそう (あそれ よいよい！)
Wasshoi wasshoi, let's dance all night (A-sore yoi yoi!)
ポッピンキャンディ☆アップル！ねえ聞いてよDreamer!
Poppin' Candy Apple! Hey, listen, Dreamer!
Check it! Check it! なんです！ Shall We Dance? (Dance!)
Check it! Check it! It's us! Shall We Dance? (Dance!)
なんてたってフィーバー！テンションはMAXで
After all, it's Fever! Tension is at MAX
もっともっと溶けちゃうくらい
More and more, until we're about to melt
いっせーので歌え！ (ちゃちゃちゃ！)
All together now, sing! (Cha cha cha!)
踊れ！ (いぇいいぇい！)
Dance! (Yay yay!)
笑え！ (ハッハッハッ！)
Laugh! (Ha ha ha!)
いい感じ！
Looking good!
ねえもう一回！ (ちゃちゃちゃ！)
Hey, one more time! (Cha cha cha!)
もう一回！ (いぇいいぇい！)
One more time! (Yay yay!)
無問題！？ (やで！)
No problem!? (Yeah!)
はい優勝！ (いぇーい！)
Yes, we win! (Yay!)
きらめく空をなぞったなら
If you trace the sparkling sky
ほんのちょっと寂しくなるね
It gets a little bit lonely
それじゃケーキもおひとつ
Then, have a piece of cake too
なんとなく笑えてきたね (おっけー！)
Somehow, I've started to laugh (OK!)
Ding Dong Dang 響くような
Like Ding Dong Dang is echoing
耳澄ませば君のBGM
If you listen closely, it's your BGM
お腹の合図が聞こえたら
When you hear the signal from your stomach
それじゃみんな宴の再開だ！
Then everyone, it's time to resume the banquet!
準備は？いただきます！
Ready? Let's eat!
ポッピンキャンディ☆フィーバー！シュワシュワなフレーバー
Poppin' Candy Fever! A fizzy flavor
パチパチなんです！ Shall We Dance? (Dance!)
It's crackling! Shall We Dance? (Dance!)
なんてたってフィーバー！夢見がちな君は
After all, it's Fever! You, the dreamer
わっしょいわっしょい踊り明かそう (あそれ よいよい！)
Wasshoi wasshoi, let's dance all night (A-sore yoi yoi!)
ポッピンキャンディ☆グレープ！ねえこっち向いてDreamer!
Poppin' Candy Grape! Hey, look this way, Dreamer!
Hurry! Hurry! あっぷっぷ Shall We Smile? (Smile!)
Hurry! Hurry! Don't laugh! Shall We Smile? (Smile!)
なんてたってフィーバー！お味はミックスで
After all, it's Fever! The flavor is a mix
もっともっと楽しんじゃって
Have more and more fun
もういっちょいけるね はいおかわり！
One more round, yes, second helping!
いくぞー！
Let's go!
ポッピンキャンディ☆フィーバー！弾けちゃえフレーバー
Poppin' Candy Fever! Let the flavor burst
Party Party なんです！ Shall We Dance? (Dance!)
It's a Party Party! Shall We Dance? (Dance!)
なんてたってフィーバー！恥ずかしがり屋も
After all, it's Fever! Even the shy ones
わっしょいわっしょい踊り明かそう (あそれ よいよい！)
Wasshoi wasshoi, let's dance all night (A-sore yoi yoi!)
ポッピンキャンディ☆ピーチ！ねえ聞いてよDreamer!
Poppin' Candy Peach! Hey, listen, Dreamer!
Check it! Check it! なんです！ Shall We Dance? (Dance!)
Check it! Check it! It's us! Shall We Dance? (Dance!)
なんてたってフィーバー！テンションはMAXで
After all, it's Fever! Tension is at MAX
もっともっとうるさいくらい
More and more, until it's almost too loud
いっせーので歌え！ (ちゃちゃちゃ！)
All together now, sing! (Cha cha cha!)
踊れ！ (いぇいいぇい！)
Dance! (Yay yay!)
笑え！ (ハッハッハッ！)
Laugh! (Ha ha ha!)
いい感じ！
Looking good!
ねえもう一回！ (ちゃちゃちゃ！)
Hey, one more time! (Cha cha cha!)
もう一回！ (いぇいいぇい！)
One more time! (Yay yay!)
お前かーっ！ (うわーい！)
Was it you!? (Uwaa-i!)
はい優勝！ (いぇーい！)
Yes, we win! (Yay!)
あー！ありがとー！大好き！よかったー！ありがとうございます！
Ah-! Thank you-! I love you! That was great! Thank you so much!
ということで、今日みこちに一緒に歌って踊ってもらいました！
And so, I had Miko-chi sing and dance with me today!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
ありがとう呼んでくれて！嬉しいです本当に。
Thank you for inviting me! I'm really happy.
嬉しいです本当に。可愛いなあ。
I'm really happy too. You're so cute.
今日もかわよだなあ。
You're cute today too.
え、ありがとう。みこちも可愛いよ。
Eh, thanks. Miko-chi is cute too.
可愛いよ。そんなことない！
You're cute. That's not true!
可愛いね！
You're cute!
そんなことない！あやめちゃん可愛いね！
That's not true! Ayame-chan is cute!
あ、本当？可愛いね！
Ah, really? You're cute!
てかあれだよね、みこちとは新衣装ぶり？こないだの。
By the way, it's been since your new outfit reveal, right? Recently.
あ、そうだね。みこの新衣装ライブに。
Ah, that's right. For Miko's new outfit live.
ねー、可愛かったよ。でも二人はちょっと初めてだよね。
Yeah, you were cute. But it's our first time as a duo, right?
そうなんだよ。二人はね、初めてなんですよ。意外とね。
That's right. It's the first time for just the two of us. Surprisingly.
え、なぜあやめちゃんはみこのこと呼んでくれたの？
Eh, why did Ayame-chan invite Miko?
え、実はね、あの...
Eh, actually, well...
ポッピンキャンディ☆フィーバーを聴いた時に、あ、絶対にみこちに合うって思ったんですよ。
When I heard 'Poppin' Candy Fever', I thought, 'Ah, this definitely suits Miko-chi.'
えー！だから一緒に歌いたいって思って誘っちゃった。
Eh-! So I thought I wanted to sing it together and invited you.
やったー！ありがとう！
Yay! Thank you!
じゃ、あやめちゃんはみこになつき始めてきたという...
So, that means Ayame-chan has started to get attached to Miko...
え、そういう目線なの？そういう目線なのよ。
Eh, is that how you see it? That's how I see it.
うん。お友達みたいな感じではなく。
Yeah. Not like we're friends or anything.
いやなんか愛玩動物みたいな。
No, it's more like a pet.
あ、そういう感じなのね。やったー。愛玩動物みたいな。
Ah, I see. Yay. Like a pet.
あの、みことあやめちゃんて意外とシナジーあるよね。
Miko and Ayame-chan have a surprising amount of synergy, don't we?
意外とね。ちょっとカメラさんちょっと引きで見えますか？
Surprisingly. Mr. Cameraman, can we get a wide shot?
ピンクで意外と可愛いんですよ二人。
The pink is surprisingly cute on us.
ね、可愛い。色合いが良きです。
Yeah, cute. The colors are good.
あとはあれだよね、鬼とお巫女だからね。
Also, it's because it's an Oni and a Miko.
あ、もしかしてこれ退治される側ですか？
Ah, is this the 'getting exorcised' side?
鬼は外！福は内！
Out with the demons! In with good fortune!
わー！ありがとう！ありがとうございます！このあとも見てね！
Wow! Thank you! Thank you so much! Keep watching after this too!
わたしの一番かわいいところ
My Cutest Part
あれ、気づいちゃいましたか？
Oh, did you notice?
生まれて30秒で最初に聞いた言葉...
The first words I heard thirty seconds after being born...
当たり前にそれ覚えてないけど嬉しかったはず
I don't remember it clearly, of course, but I should have been happy
今でもだいたいのことは変わってないって言うこっちゃ
It means that mostly things haven't changed even now
中身は変わっていますのでその辺でも評価
Since the inside has changed, please evaluate that part too
お願い
Please
携帯のアンテナを光らせて
Light up your phone antenna
それが超キュートなあの頃だって知っていたり
Knowing that it's that super cute time
って言うかアンテナって何って言ってるの？
Wait, what do you mean by 'antenna'?
私に付き合ってくれるの好き
I like it when you hang out with me
逆にでも私のどこが好き？
But on the other hand, what do you like about me?
ねぇねぇねぇ！
Hey, hey, hey!
私の1番かわいいところに気付いてる？
Have you noticed my cutest part?
そんな君が1番すごいすごいよすごすぎる
You're the most amazing, amazing, too amazing
そして君が知ってる私が1番かわいいな
And the me that you know is the cutest
私もそれに気付いた
I noticed that too
だからそれかわいい あれかわいいなんて
So saying that's cute, this is cute
誰かいい それかわいいなんて
Saying someone's nice, that's cute
言わないで 私以外なんてやだ
Don't say it, I don't want anyone but me
なんてありえない
That's impossible
私、気付いちゃいました
I noticed
毎日何十度も褒められまくったお菓子は
Sweets that were praised dozens of times every day
他よりちょっと甘くなるって前に聞いた
I heard before that they get a little sweeter than others
そんな...
Like that...
さすがにそれは引くんだけど私は言われたいタイプですし
That's a bit much, but I'm the type who wants to be told
もっと分かりやすくていいんだよ お待ちしてらっす
It's okay to be more obvious, I'm waiting
お願い
Please
何しててもどんな顔見せてても
No matter what I'm doing or what kind of face I'm showing
いつも超キュートだって確信してるのは
The reason I'm sure I'm always super cute is
なんだかさ 知らなかったタイプの運命の人なの？
Somehow, are you a type of fated person I didn't know?
付き合ったよ無理ごめん
I went out with you, no way sorry
逆にでもそれより楽しいよ
But conversely, it's more fun than that
ねぇねぇねぇ！
Hey, hey, hey!
私の1番かわいいところをよく見てる
You're looking closely at my cutest part
そんな君が本当に超ラッキーな人すぎる
You're really just too super lucky
そして君が何年経ってもそう思えるように
And so that you'll feel that way no matter how many years pass
私はそれに気付いた
I noticed that
会えないときもどんな表情してるかとか
When we can't meet, what kind of expression I'm making
気持ち悪くない想像しちゃうかな
I might imagine things that aren't gross
それかわいい あれかわいいよって
Saying that's cute, this is cute
本当にかわいいって言って
Tell me I'm really cute
私の1番かわいいところに気付いてる？
Have you noticed my cutest part?
そんな君が1番すごいすごいよすごすぎる
You're the most amazing, amazing, too amazing
そして君が知ってる私が1番かわいいな
And the me that you know is the cutest
私もそれに気付いた
I noticed that too
私の1番かわいいところをよく見てる
You're looking closely at my cutest part
そんな君が本当に超ラッキーな人すぎる
You're really just too super lucky
そして君が何年経ってもそう思えるように
And so that you'll feel that way no matter how many years pass
私はそれに気付いた
I noticed that
私の1番かわいいところに気付いてる？
Have you noticed my cutest part?
そんな君が1番すごいすごいよすごすぎる
You're the most amazing, amazing, too amazing
そして君が知ってる私が1番かわいいの
And the me that you know is the cutest
私もそれに気付いた
I noticed that too
だからそれかわいい あれかわいいなんて
So saying that's cute, this is cute
誰かいい それかわいいなんて
Saying someone's nice, that's cute
言わないで 私以外なんてやだ
Don't say it, I don't want anyone but me
やだ！
No way!
なんてありえない
That's impossible
いぇーい！
Yay!
みんなありがとうございます、来てくれて！
Thank you everyone for coming!
あやめ先輩！4周年おめでとうございます！
Ayame-senpai! Happy 4th Anniversary!
ありがとー！嬉しい！
Thank you! I'm so happy!
今日はちょっとね、ラミィちゃんとぺこらと、かなたんとマリンに来ていただきましたー！
Today, I had Lamy-chan, Pekora, Kanatan, and Marine come over!
いぇーい！
Yay!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
しかも、こっちのお二人は初めて3Dで...
And what's more, these two are for the first time in 3D...
そうなんですよー！
That's right!
ありがと、本当に。
Thank you, really.
ちょっとね、この曲はもう余が、絶対この子はこの子が合うっていうのを選んで来てもらったメンバーでもあるので、めちゃ嬉しいです。
Well, for this song, I chose these members because I felt they would absolutely suit it, so I'm very happy.
っていうことは、1番かわいいって思ってくれてる...
Does that mean you think we're the cutest...
かわいいメンバー、かわいいメンバー
Cute members, cute members
お、みんなかわいい！
Oh, everyone is cute!
1番だれがかわいいのかなぁ？
I wonder who is the cutest?
え、あやめ先輩でしょ！
Eh, it's Ayame-senpai, right!
え、余もかわいい！？
Eh, am I cute too!?
負けた... 負けちゃった...
I lost... I lost...
や、でもあやめ先輩、今回のライブ全体通して船長最近よく見るちょっと...
Well, but Ayame-senpai, throughout this whole live, Senchou has been seeing you often lately...
TikTok...
おぉー！
Whoa!
この曲知ってるぺこ？
You know this song, Peko?
分かりましたか？ちょっとTikTokで流行ってる曲を詰め込んだんですけど。
Did you notice? I packed in a lot of songs that are trending on TikTok.
いいじゃないですか！
Isn't that nice!
流行りに乗ってる！
You're following the trends!
さすがですね。すごいですね！
As expected. That's amazing!
しかもね、気づいたんですけど、このメンバー、赤と青がね、分かれてるの！
And also, I noticed something. These members are split into Red and Blue!
あ、本当だ！本当だ！
Oh, you're right! You're right!
めっちゃ一緒。見て見て見て！
It's a perfect match. Look, look, look!
こっちは、ラミィちゃん、ぺこら、かなたの、青組チーム！
Over here is Lamy-chan, Pekora, and Kanata—the Blue Team!
え、めっちゃ統一感ある。すごーい！
It feels so unified. Amazing!
でもほら、なんか、可愛いうちら、ほら。イェーイ。色気、色気。
But look, we're the cute ones. See? Yeah, sexy, sexy.
ちょっと、色気、色気、色気組だね。これはちょっと鬼組だね。
Yeah, we're the 'alluring' team, aren't we? This is quite an 'oni' combo.
ちょっと、これはちょっと、許せないでしょ。
Wait, we can't let that slide.
はっけよーい、のこった、のこった、のこった！うりゃー！
Ready... go! Fight, fight, fight! Uryaa!
うわぁー！強い！
Whoa! They're strong!
ナイス、ナイス！
Nice, nice!
青組強すぎるー！
The Blue Team is too strong!
帰りましょっか！帰りましょ！バイバイ！
Shall we head home? Let's go home! Bye-bye!
全員やるの？全員行っちゃうの？あやめを残しすぎだろう。
Wait, everyone's leaving? Is everyone going? You're leaving Ayame all alone!
あれ？あれ？グッズ紹介あるよ！バイバイ！
Wait? Wait! I still have the goods intro! Bye-bye!
お待たせしました！グッズ紹介のお時間です！
Thank you for waiting! It's time for the goods introduction!
ということで、皆さんお気づきかと思いますが、百鬼あやめ活動４周年記念グッズでーす！
As you might have guessed, it's time for Nakiri Ayame's 4th Anniversary commemorative goods!
やったー！皆さんお待ちかねの嬉しいお知らせですよー！
Yay! Here's the exciting news you've all been waiting for!
ということでグッズ紹介していきましょう！まずは、こちら！
So, let's get into the goods! First up, this!
ドーン！見てください！ワイドラバーマットです！じゃじゃーん！
Ta-da! Take a look! It's the Wide Rubber Mat! Boom!
こちらはね、Hina先生に描き下ろししていただきました。
This illustration was specially drawn by Hina-sensei.
ちょっと、いつもの余と雰囲気が...みたいなことは受け付けておりませんけれども。
I won't accept comments like 'She looks a bit different than usual'... even though she does.
めちゃくちゃ可愛いラバーマット描いていただきました。ありがとうございます。
It's an incredibly cute rubber mat illustration. Thank you so much.
そして、そして、まだありますよ！続いて、こちら！
And there's more! Next is this!
アクリルジオラマスタンドです！めっちゃこれ可愛いでしょ！
The Acrylic Diorama Stand! Isn't this super cute?
これも、せんちゃ先生に描き下ろしいただきました。ありがとうございます。めっちゃ可愛いよ！
This was drawn by Sencha-sensei. Thank you! It's so cute!
そして、そして、まだまだありますよ！次は、こちら！
And we're not done yet! Next up is this!
ステンレスサーモタンブラーです！これね、アクリルジオラマと同じせんちゃ先生に描いていただきました。
The Stainless Thermo Tumbler! This was also drawn by Sencha-sensei, just like the diorama.
めちゃくちゃ可愛い。これでね、冷たい水飲んでください、みんな。
It's so adorable. Use this to drink cold water, everyone.
水分補給大事だと思うので。冷たいとか、あったかいとか、使ってください、ぜひ。
Hydration is important. Whether it's cold or hot, please use it.
そして、そして、まだありますよ！続いて、こちら！
And there's still more! Next is this!
ぽよ余ティッシュカバーです！見て、超可愛くないですか？
The Poyoyo Tissue Cover! Look, isn't it super cute?
ちょっと待って、余の手元にぽよ余があるの。はい！
Wait a sec, I have a Poyoyo right here with me. Here!
よいしょー！可愛いねー！こちらのぽよ余のティッシュカバーが出ます！
Heave-ho! So cute! This Poyoyo tissue cover is being released!
めちゃ可愛い！お部屋に置いて。ティッシュって多分日常的に使うと思うので。
It's so cute! Keep it in your room. Since you probably use tissues every day.
ぜひお部屋に置いて使ってほしいなって。「使ってほしいよー」ってぽよ余も言ってます。
I'd love for you to have it in your room. 'I want to be used!' Poyoyo says.
さらにさらに大事なこと言い忘れてた！シチュエーションボイス、「デビュー記念お花見デート」もちゃんと付いてきますよ。
And I almost forgot something very important! A Situation Voice, 'Debut Anniversary Hanami Date', is also included.
余のボイスもぜひ聴いてください。
Please give my voice recording a listen.
数量限定バージョンは、余の直筆サインと複製メッセージ入りポストカードが付いてきます！
The limited edition set comes with a postcard featuring my handwritten signature and a printed message!
頑張って直筆サイン書くのでぜひ皆さんゲットしてください。数量限定なのでお早めに！
I'll do my best to sign them, so please get one! They're limited, so be quick!
お早めにお願いします。
Please get yours soon.
通常版は、余の複製サインと複製メッセージ入りポストカードとなっています。ぜひゲットしてください。
The regular version includes a postcard with a printed signature and message. Please check it out.
そしてですね、数量限定と通常版も特典では、ちょっと初めての試みなんですけれども。
And as a bonus for both sets... this is a first for me.
余のASMRボイス、「お花見のあとで」が付いてきまーす。
My ASMR voice recording, 'After the Hanami', will be included!
ちょっとASMRは緊張したんですけど、初めてなんでね。
I was a bit nervous recording ASMR, since it was my first time.
ぜひ「お花見のあとで」のASMRボイス、恥ずかしいですが聴いていただけると嬉しいです。
It's a bit embarrassing, but I'd be happy if you'd listen to the 'After the Hanami' ASMR voice.
ということで皆さんぜひゲットしてください！
So, everyone, please be sure to get your set!
ということで、みんなライブどうでしたか？
Anyway, how did everyone enjoy the live stream?
ね、みんな可愛かったでしょう。歌って踊って頑張ってくださったので。
Everyone was so cute, right? They all worked so hard singing and dancing.
本当に余は満足です。嬉しいです、本当に。
I'm truly satisfied. I'm so happy, really.
#百鬼あやめ4周年記念
#NakiriAyame4thAnniversary
新しくなってね、もう嬉しい…
It's all been refreshed, and I'm so happy...
この後は！
And after this!
なとは？
After this what?
なんと！なんとですよ！
What's more! Listen to this!
メンバーシップ限定の配信があります！
There will be a membership-exclusive stream!
ちょこっとあります！見てください、ぜひ！
It'll just be a short one! Please come and watch!
え、そちらをね…夏…夏といえば？
And there... summer... speaking of summer?
夏といえばあの衣装が…
Speaking of summer, that outfit...
…見られるかもしれないよ！（ハハハ！）
...might be seen! (Laughs)
え、ということでぜひ、メンバーシップ限定の配信も見てくださると嬉しいです！
So, I'd be happy if you'd come watch the membership-exclusive stream too!
ということでぜひみんなグッズ買ってね！
So, everyone, please make sure to buy the merch!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
Happiness to you
Nakiri Ayame 4th Anniversary